# **Anatoliy Yastreb**

# **Software Engineer**

Bilker Allee 196, Düsseldorf, Germany 40215 +49 177 7817203

> anatoliy.yastreb@gmail.com https://ayastreb.me

I'm a web software engineer with 5 years of experience in eCommerce and overall 10 years of experience in web development. I've led teams of 3 to 4 developers and have experience setting up team workflow according to industry's best practices.

I'm passionate about complete process of product development - from requirements collection to deployment and impact analysis. I enjoy working with smart people, crafting software which brings value to customers, and continuously improving my skills.

In my free time I contribute to open source projects and learn new technologies such as Ruby, AngularJS, ReactJS and others.

# Experience

### Senior Software Developer at Luxury Fashion Trade GmbH (fashionette.de)

Düsseldorf, Germany, 2013 - 2016

Technologies: Magento, PHP, Laravel, Solr, Varnish, Microservices

Led development team of 3-4 in various projects, including new features implementation, payment methods integration and online shop localization in 16 new countries for Germany's biggest online designer handbags retailer.

# Senior Software Engineer at Magento, X.commerce, Inc. (an eBay company)

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2011 – 2013

Technologies: PHP, SOAP WSI, REST, Redis, MongoDB, Gearman

Worked on Magento Core API, performed R&D on Magento 2 API platform. Participated in Magento Connect and Magento GO (SaaS) projects development.

## Web Developer as Independent Contractor

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2007 – 2010

Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, AWS, Solr

Implemented various projects, such as <u>DiccionarioLibre.com</u>, <u>ProfileStar.com</u>, <u>MyCubi.com</u>

# Junior PHP Developer at eTek Systems

Dnipropetrovsk, Ukraine, 2006 - 2007

Technologies: PHP, XML, Atom

Worked on international customer's web projects and in-house tools.

# **Projects**

#### **Meal Planner**

#### Founder & Primary Developer, 2015 - Present

Recipe recommendation and nutrition balancing service.

A health & fitness progressive web app built with AngularJS, Sinatra & ElasticSearch.

#### **Jekyll**

#### Team Captain, 2016 - Present

As @jekyll/build team captain I help triaging incoming issues, review pull requests and occasionally contribute to bug fixes, refactoring and feature development.

#### Jekyll Maps

#### Maintainer, 2016 - Present

A plugin that allows users to easily create different Google Maps on a Jekyll site.

#### **Bandwidth Hero**

#### Maintainer, 2016 - Present

Experimental Chrome extension which compresses images on the page via proxy server. Proxy server is implemented with Node.js.

### Education

#### Coursera

Data Structures and Algorithms, 2016

#### **Udacity**

Tech Entrepreneur Nanodegree, 2015 – 2016

### National Mining University, Dnepropetrovsk, Ukraine

Bachelor, Management, Economics, 2004 – 2008

#### Skills

Languages

PHP, Ruby, JavaScript

**Frameworks** 

Zend, Laravel, Sinatra, AngularJS

WebServices

SOAP, REST, JSON API, oAuth

**Databases & Search** 

MySQL, Redis, ElasticSearch, Solr

**Testing** 

PHPUnit, Rspec, Selenium, Jasmine

**Continuous Integration** 

Bamboo, Capistrano, TravisCI